JACK PIERCE



+44 7456 429 035



jacktpierce11@gmail.com



132 Mottingham Road, SE9 4SL, London

PROFILE

I am a motivated and enthusiastic individual with a passion for learning and an inquisitive, analytical mindset. I enjoy tackling complex problems and have developed independence, problem-solving skills, and cultural awareness through my experiences living and travelling abroad.

EDUCATION

2.1 MASTERS PHYSICS WITH PHILOSOPHY 2016-2020

The University of Manchester

Masters Physics Project - Research and experimental project on magnetic nanobots

Relevant courses - Mathematics 1 & 2, Vibrations and Waves, Statistical Mechanics, Mathematics of Waves and Fields, Introduction to Non-Linear Physics, Philosophy of Language

PORTFOLIO



https://jackpierce11.github.io/



www.kaggle.com/jackpierce

SKILLS

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Matlab (used in Physics projects)
- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- Data Visualisation
- SQL (familiar)

LANGUAGES

SPANISH (ADVANCED) - C1 PORTUGUESE - B2

PROJECTS

PREDICTING PREMIER LEAGUE MATCH WINNERS

- Conducted data preprocessing, feature engineering, and selection on a dataset of 1389 football matches, with 27 features.
- Implemented various ML models, including K-nearest neighbour, logistic regression and a random forest classifier and achieved an accuracy of 73%.

PREDICTING HOUSE PRICE VALUE

- Carried out EDA, data cleaning and feature engineering and selection on a dataset of 2919 houses with 80 features. Scored RMSE of 0.13205 comparing the log of prediction and actual values. Placed in top 25% Kaggle competition.
- Trained various regression models (Ridge, Lasso, XGBoost and Random Forest Regressor) and combined their predictions to mitigate overfitting.

EXPERIENCES ABROAD

- After graduating, saved up money for 18 months while self-studying Spanish before living and travelling in Mexico and Brazil for 11 months
- Became proficient in Spanish (C1) and learned Portuguese to a high level (B2)
 while teaching over 500 lessons of English online to fund travels
- Volunteered in a hostel for two months, gaining independence and problemsolving skills while exploring different cultures
- Started self-studying data skills using online courses and projects while abroad

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

BAR SUPERVISOR (LUXURY EVENTS)

Thames Luxury Charters LTD

June 2016 - Dec 2021, Dec 2022-present

- Communicating with client event organisers for events of up to 200 guests
- Trained over 15 members of staff and supervising up to 5 bartenders
- Helping with logistics of bar stock over 4 bars using Excel